

Steve Martin

Solution Architect

SC Cleared

About Me

A Solution Architect, with a background in software/DevOps engineering with many years of experience working within the Public sector on the Capgemini HMRC account.

I am comfortable shaping solutions and strategy, as well as leading project delivery to take a solution through implementation and deployment. I have also retained my technical skills to enable me to take a hands-on role when its necessary.

My specialism is in solutions being designed and delivered into AWS.

Highlights

- Solution Architect
- Product Development
- DevOps Engineering
- Process Improvements
- Troubleshooting
- Network Topology

Contact Details

Address:

Telford, Shropshire

Mobile:

07523874718

Email:

Steve.a. martin 1982@gmail.com

Experience

Capgemini (HMRC Account) 2006 - present

Solution Architecture 2016 - present

Undertaken many roles across pre-sale, consulting and delivery. Delivery role ranges from engagements lasting a few weeks, through to large scale implementation projects.

Clients have included HMRC (Her Majesty's Revenue & Customs), Valuation Office Agency (VOA), Bayer, CCP (Capgemini Cloud Platform).

Responsibilities have varied with role; examples of recent roles are:

Solution Architect:

Design and deliver DevOps platform hosted within AWS for Bayer.

Responsibilities included:

Pre-sales; Producing and owning end to end solution; managing a team of DevOps engineers; tool integration into clients Azure AD and connectivity into existing cloud platforms and on-premise datacentre.

Solution Architect:

Design and deliver VOAs ALM (Application Lifecycle Management) and DevOps platform into AWS.

Responsibilities included:

Working with the client to define requirements; leading a team of engineers to deliver the solution within ambitious timescales; ensuing security compliance; aligning with ISO27001.

Integration Architect:

Delivering an integration platform into AWS and designing, monitoring and service desk integrations.

Responsibilities included: Pre-sale; customer demos; defining standardised interfaces; producing RabbitMQ deployment standards; documenting interface workflows.

Solution Architect:

Designed, delivered and also participated in the engineering of HMRCs new ITSM solution in the cloud, which is used to manage the lifecycle of IT services across the estate.

Responsibilities included:

Understanding HMRC IT strategy to ensure alignment; managing client's expectations; used automation to deploy infrastructure using Ansible; supporting client training during hand-over;

Solution Architect:

Producing architecture patterns and best practices for HMRC as they migrate, or design new solutions destined for the cloud.

Responsibilities included:

Providing infrastructure deployment patterns across Azure and AWS, from non-resilient to fully resilient including auto-scaling groups; document failure scenarios and service impact depending on pattern adopted.

Skills and Abilities

Cloud Platforms

- AWS
- Azure

Development Languages

- Shell
- Bash
- Pearl
- PowerShell
- Java

Operating Systems

- Windows
- Linux

Tools & Technologies

- ADFS
- Azure AD
- SQL Server
- Puppet
- Ansible
- Vagrant
- Nginx
- Zabbix
- Spacewalk
- Puppet
- Ansible
- RabbitMQ
- WS02
- OpenVPN

DevOps Engineering

Developed a "managed test service" for HMRC, which provided a suite of testing tools, allowing the client to perform automated testing against inhouse developed applications.

Responsibilities included:

Wrote Terraform code to automate infrastructure deployments and Puppet manifests and modules to configure and manage servers; created CIS benchmark hardened images; ensured infrastructure was fully immutable.

Technical Project Manager 2012-2015

Managing a large team of network engineers to deliver network changes and infrastructure into key HMRC datacenters and offices across the UK.

Responsibilities included:

Managed complex implementations, ensuring minimal service downtime to mitigate reputational risk; managed key stakeholders; project reporting both internally and externally to the client; managing overall plan and costs.

Projects included:

- PSN (Public Sector Network) WAN
- Fortinet firewalls
- HSO (High Speed Office).
- VoIP (Voice over IP)

Lead Software Engineer 2006 - 2012

Designing, developing and Supporting application within a complex estate. including and not limited to Citrix XenApp Administrator, Experian Payment Gateway.

Responsibilities included:

Managing team of engineers; troubleshooting live issues; out of hours support; planning and assigning work; customer facing; system improvements;

Certification / Training

- Citrix 5.0 Administrator
- Windows 2012 administrator
- Architecting in AWS
- · Architecting in Azure
- AWS Solution Architect Associate (scheduled Nov 2019)

Interests and Activities

I'm an active person, play football on a regular basis, member of a gym and enjoy the outdoors with my family. Like to undertake DIY projects around my house and get under the bonnet of my car when issues occur. Love a challenge and never one to give up.

Education

New Collage Telford - NVQ & BTEC Science

Wrockwardine Wood School Telford